A Guide to the Powhatan County (Va.) Fiduciary Records, 1770-1934
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Powhatan County (Va.) Fiduciary Records 1770-1934
Library of Virginia
1049876-1049949 circa,1119391- 1178743 circa, 1186818-1188799, 0007326978
16.1 cu.ft. (34 boxes)
Powhatan County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Powhatan County.
Historical Information
Powhatan County was named for the paramount chief of the Powhatan Indians in the tidewater of Virginia in the late sixteenth and early years of the seventeenth century. It was formed from Cumberland County in 1777, and part of Chesterfield County was added in 1850.
Scope and Content
Powhatan County (Va.) Fiduciary Records, 1770-1934, include miscellaneous records filed in a local court by trustees, administrators, executors, guardians, and committees that related to the performance of their duties managing a person's estate. These records typically include the following; bonds, appraisements, audits, inventories, accounts, estate divisions, settlements, dowery records, etc. Information related to enslaved people are commonly found in these records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Powhatan County records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm.
Contents List
- Fiduciary Records, 1821-1827 circa
  Contains accounts, inventories, appraisals, bonds, guardian bonds
- Fiduciary Records, 1770-1817
  Fiduciary Records, 1770-1817, (bulk 1812-1817), circa: accounts, inventories, appraisals, bonds, guardian bonds (unprocessed)
- Fiduciary Records, 1817-1821
  Fiduciary Records, 1817-1821, circa: accounts, inventories, appraisals, bonds, guardian bonds; unprocessed
- Fiduciary Records, 1830-1867
  Fiduciary Records, 1830-1867, circa: accounts, inventories, appraisals, bonds, guardian bonds; unprocessed
- Fiduciary Records, 1856-1871
  Fiduciary Records, 1856-1871, circa: accounts, inventories, appraisals, bonds, guardian bonds; unprocessed
- Fiduciary Records, 1840-1850
  Fiduciary Records include miscellaneous records filed in a local court by trustees, administrators, executors, guardians, and committees that related to the performance of their duties managing a person's estate. These records typically include the following; bonds, appraisements, audits, inventories, accounts, estate divisions, settlements, dowery records, etc. Information related to enslaved people are commonly found in these records.
- Fiduciary Records, 1827-1835
- Fiduciary Records, 1827-1830
- Fiduciary Records, 1838-1842
- Fiduciary Records, 1827-1835
- Fiduciary Records, 1848-1853
- Fiduciary Records, 1872-1896
- Fiduciary Records, 1841-1846
- Fiduciary Records, 1850-1867
  Fiduciary Records, 1850-1867: accounts, inventories, appraisals, reports; includes a plat of land of John Spear's children, 1867
- Fiduciary Records, 1897-1927
- Fiduciary Records, 1816-1824
  Fiduciary Records, 1816-1824: inventories and appraisements, bonds, orders, accounts and sales, reports, assignments of dower (includes plat of Sarah Matthews, dower, 1824); divisions of land and slaves